Nawar Yossef

nawaryossef2@gmail.com 205-826-3790 Atlanta, GA

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

GitHub: github.com/NawarYossef **LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/nawaryossef **Portfolio:** nawaryossef.netlify.com

Summary

Fullstack JavaScript developer candidate skilled in writing clean, testable UI code. Experienced with React, Node, vanilla JavaScript, MongoDB, jQuery and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Experienced with modern tooling and excited to pick up the right tools for the job.

Skills

Advanced: JavaScript, React, Redux, Node.js, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs. **Proficient:** MongoDB, Express.js, TDD with Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Jest, Enzyme, Browserify, ES6. **Expert:** Written & verbal communication, classical music.

Recent Projects

<u>SaveMyTrip</u>: A fullstack app for users to save and email flight information. Built with Node.js, MongoDB, JavaScript, Express, jQuery, Mocha.js, Chai.js. Uses the SendGrind API.

<u>Hot or Cold</u>: A front-end app where users attempt to guess a randomly generated number. Built with React and Redux.

<u>Grub n Grapes</u>: An app developed with API integration to help users find food and wine venues. Built with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Express and jQuery. Uses the Google Maps and Foursquare APIs.

Calculator: A calculator app developed with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express.js, Bootstrap and jQuery.

Experience

SELF EMPLOYED Tuscaloosa, AL Piano Instructor Dec 2016 – present

- Provided online piano lessons for a studio of 15+ students.
- Developed lesson plans and maintained a list of diverse students in age and background.
- Engaged students in discussions on music theory and history.

FREELANCE Tuscaloosa, AL

Concert Pianist April 2010 – May 2017

- Won several international piano competitions.
- Awarded full-scholarships from several domestic and international universities.
- Performed numerous solo and chamber music recitals.
- Participated in several music festivals in France, United Kingdom, Egypt and North America.
- Performed with a number of orchestras in North America.

THE UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA

Tuscaloosa, AL Aug 2012 – May 2016

Graduate Teaching Assistant

- University pianist and organist.
- Teaching assistant for choral conducting and choir classes.
- Accompanied music students in various chamber settings.
- University Carillon player.
- Piano accompanist for vocal lessons.

Education

THINKFUL Graduation Date

Full Stack Flex Program

June 2018 (anticipated)

- Created and deployed mobile-first fullstack applications while learning new languages and frameworks.
- Collaborated several hours every week with a senior web developer and applied industry best practices.
- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js, React, Redux, MongoDB and jQuery.
- Gained experience with up to date advanced technologies including Passport.js, npm, Yarn, Heroku, Netlify, Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code and Sublime Text.
- Applied unit and integration testing using Mocha.js, Chai.js, Jest, Enzyme and Travis Cl.

THE UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA

Masters of Music in Organ Performance

Graduation Date

• Performed several organ recitals to fulfill degree requirements.

- May 2015
- Studied music performance, organ pedagogy, music composition, music theory and music history.
- Awarded the Loiz Boozer Douglas and Robert Nicolosi scholarships.
- Awarded the University Presbyterian Church Fellowship.

CONVERSE COLLEGE

Masters of Music in Piano Performance

Graduation Date

• Studied piano performance and pedagogy with Dr. Douglas Weeks.

May 2010

- Performed piano and organ in several College events and concerts.
- Awarded full assistantship accompanying instrumentalists and choirs.